fai.ie 2013-12-20

# Football Association of Ireland - FAI Privacy Statement

**General**  
The Football Association of Ireland (FAI) respects your privacy and has created this statement to demonstrate our commitment to protecting it. In general you can visit the FAI on the web without identifying yourself and we will not collect any personal information about you on our website without your clear permission. Any information you do submit will be treated strictly in accordance with the Data Protection Acts, 1988 and 2003.

**Scope**  
The FAI websites are www.fai.ie, www.airtricityleague.ie, www.summersoccerschools.ie, wnl.fai.ie, coaching.fai.ie, away.fai.ie, mcdonaldsfuturefootball.fai.ie & www.thirdlevelfootball.ie. This statement outlines our privacy policy with regard to these websites. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other linked websites.

**Technical Information**  
Technical details of your visit to FAI websites are recorded. These include IP addresses, browser details and web search terms. This information will only be used for statistical and site management purposes. And to help us make our site more user friendly.

**Contact details:**  
The FAI can be contacted at the address below for queries or any complaints relating to the Privacy Statement or our data protection policy: Email: [privacy@fai.ie](mailto:privacy@fai.ie) Telephone: +353 (1) 899 9500 Post: Football Association of Ireland, National Sports Campus Ireland, Abbotstown, Dublin 15, Ireland.

**Personal Information**  
The FAI will not collect any personal data about you on its website, apart from information, which is submitted via web forms, or information volunteered via email. Any information provided in this manner, is not made available to any third parties, and is used by the FAI solely for the purposes for which it is provided and will not be added to a mailing list nor made available to third parties. On some occasions you may be able to order products or services, request information, subscribe to marketing or support materials, register yourself, or apply for a job at the FAI. The types of personal information you provide to us on these pages may include name, postal address, phone number, e-mail address, user IDs and passwords, billing and transaction information, credit card information, contact preferences, educational and employment background and job interest data.

To personalise our websites, services or communications and improve our products and services, we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, and experiences with our products or services. Providing this additional information is optional.

**Non-personal information**  
This includes data about usage and service operation that is not associated with a specific personal identity. The FAI collects and analyses non-personal information to evaluate how visitors use the FAI websites.

**Cookies**  
Cookies are small text files that a website can use in order to recognise visitors who revisit a site so as to facilitate their ongoing access to and use of the site. It enables usage behaviour to be tracked and aggregate data to be compiled that would facilitate more targeted advertising and improved content. Typically, cookies involve the assigning of a unique number to the visitor. One simple way to prevent the use of cookies it to activate the facility which is available in most web browsers that enables the user to deny or accept cookies. However, visitors should realise that certain cookies may be necessary in order to provide the visitor with certain features such as the customised delivery of certain information.

If you don’t want to receive cookies, you can modify your browser so that it notifies you when cookies are sent to it or you can refuse cookies altogether. You can also delete cookies that have already been set.

If you wish to restrict or block web browser cookies which are set on your device then you can do this through your browser settings; the Help function within your browser should tell you how. Alternatively, you may wish to visit [www.aboutcookies.org,](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which contains comprehensive information on how to do this on a wide variety of desktop browsers.

**Children's Privacy**  
The FAI is committed to protecting the privacy needs of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests.

**How the FAI uses your information**  
The FAI uses your personal information to provide you with information, products or services and to help us better understand your needs and interests. Specifically, we may use your information to help you complete a transaction or order, to communicate with you, to provide service and support, to update you on services and benefits, to personalize promotional offers and to personalise FAI websites. We will disclose your information to your service providers and agents for these purposes. Occasionally we may also use your information to contact you for market research regarding FAI products or services. We will give you the opportunity to choose your privacy preferences regarding such communications.

**Who the FAI shares your information with**  
The FAI will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others. The FAI will not share your personal information with third parties except in responding to your requests for products or services. Your permission will be requested when you submit your information. The FAI may share customer information across FAI departments. The FAI will not share personal information with any other third parties without your permission, unless required by law .

**Your privacy preference and opting out**  
To opt-out of receiving communications you have expressly requested (such as e-mail newsletters etc.), use any of the following methods:

  * Select the e-mail "opt-out" or "unsubscribe" link, or follow the opt-out instructions included in each subscription communication
  * Write to the FAI Webmaster, [webmaster@fai.ie](mailto:webmaster@fai.ie) \- be sure to provide your name, e-mail and postal address, and relevant information about your FAI registrations.

**Access to and accuracy of your information**  
The FAI strives to keep your personal information accurate. You may write to the FAI Webmaster at any time to rectify any inaccurate data recorded about you. There is no charge for this facility.  
We will provide you with access to your information on request by writing to the FAI Webmaster with a postal order/cheque or bank draft for €6.00 together with proof of identity.

**Retention of Data**  
The FAI shall ensure that data is not kept which is unnecessary or which is no longer used under this privacy policy. The FAI shall review its data policy on regular occasions to ensure unnecessary data is deleted. Credit Card details shall not be kept once a transaction has been finalised unless you ask us to retain your credit card information for future purchases

**Security**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Once we receive your email transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

**Changes to this statement**  
If there are updates to the terms of FAI's Privacy Statement, we will post those changes on our website www.fai.ie and update the revision date in this document, so you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have.
